Ujjwal Bera

Senior Web Developer

Bonhijli, Khanakul, Hooghly, WB, 712417 (+91) 9883266203 bera.ujjwal@hotmail.com Skype: ujjwalbera

SUMMARY

I'm a Senior Software Developer, with over 11+ years of experience in Applications Design, Development, Team Management and expertise in skills like JavaScript, NodeJs, ReactJs, PHP, Laravel, Redis, AWS and Docker. I help build an effective web presence and user experience to help grow their brand aligned with the company's business proposition.

PROJECTS

Vision

Vision is a University management system including a student registration & Attendance system. This Application has multiple microservices to build. To manage API Get Way, I have created one Nodejs microservices.

Technologies: NodeJs, React, MongoDB, AWS

Kalibra

This Application helps people take intentional steps toward optimal health. As a base framework, I have used express. For authentication, I have used jsonwebtoken. Validatorjs for input validation. Multer for file upload.

Technologies: NodeJs, React, MongoDB, SSR, AWS Cognito

Shiksha Bandhu

Shiksha Bandhu's key purpose is to bring children to light and to guide them to their complete growth. As a base framework, I have used express. I have used sequelize ORM. I also did Razorpay integration.

Technologies: NodeJs, React, React Native, MySql

SKILLS

Primary:

JavaScript, NodeJs, MongoDB, Mysql, Postgres

Secondary:

ReactJs, PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter, Redis, AWS, Docker

EDUCATION

HS

NRCA, Hooghly

2006

I have finished my V to HS from NRCA.

e-DAST CMC, Kolkata

Nov 2007 - Nov 2010

I have done 3 years of e-Diploma in Advanced Software Technology.

PHP NIST, Kolkata

Nov 2010 - Jan 2011

I have done Advance PHP training from NIST Garia.

QuickBooks Connector (Online/Desktop)

QuickBooks Connector is a microservice for syncing data between TracktraceRx and QuickBooks. As a base framework, I have used express. For authentication, I have used jsonwebtoken. For multi-language I have used i18n. I have worked on this project for 1 year and 4 months. We have 3 members in this project.

Technologies: Nodejs, React, MongoDB

ANVISA

It is a microservice that will enable software to run businesses in Brazil as per Brazil government requirements. Along with tracktrace, I have worked on this project for 7 months. We have 3 members in this project.

Technologies: NodeJs, React, MongoDB

TracktraceRx

TracktraceRx is a supply chain, logistics, and operations for manufacturers, distributors, wholesalers, or growing small businesses. As a base framework I have used express. For authentication I have used jsonwebtoken. For multi language I have used i18n. For data export I also used fast-csv. I have worked in this project 2 years 3 month. We have 16 members in this project.

Technologies: PHP, NodeJs, React, Redis, Docker, ELK Stack, PostgreSQL, Neo4J

DayInterpreting

DayInterpreting is a Phone Interpreter on Demand to Connect You with the World. It is an on-demand, real-time, OPI solution from Day Translations.

 ${\bf Technologies: Code Igniter, Java Script, Twilio, Postgre SQL}$

Nepal Bhutan Import & Export

We have created an application for Kolkata port to import & export goods from Nepal & Bhutan.

Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, MySql

LANGUAGES

Bengali, English, Hindi

ONLINE CERTIFICATES

Front End Development
Libraries
300 hours of coursework.

300 hours of coursework.

By freeCodeCamp.org

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures 300 hours of coursework. By freeCodeCamp.org

PROFICIENCY

- * Communicate Clearly and Effectively.
- * Analytical and Decision-Making Skills.
- * Work in a Pressurized situation.
- * Enthusiast in New ideas and Work.

ONLINE PROFILES



<u>/beraujjwal</u>



/in/beraujjwal/



/beraujjwal

EXPERIENCE

Matrix Media Solutions (p) ltd. — Senior Web Developer

Nov 2021 to till

In Matrix Media Solutions, I am now working as a Senior Web Developer, my main responsibilities are application architecture design. Also R&D and implementation of new technologies like loopback, SSR.

aQb Solutions Pvt. Ltd. — Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2019 to Nov 2021

In aQb Solutions Pvt. Ltd. I am now working as a Senior Software Engineer, my responsibilities are developing and designing applications using the latest and stable technologies. Regular updation of applications for security and stability purposes.

Theism Technologies — Senior Software Developer

Apr 2014 to Feb 2019

Worked and managed backend and frontend projects using technologies like WordPress, NodeJs, ReactJS, Codeigniter, CakePHP, Laravel, and Lumen. Lead a team of 6 developers using agile scrum. I was highly focused on maintaining the code optimized and also introducing new technologies to team members.

Abson Infotech — Senior Php Developer

Nov 2013 to Apr 2014

I have joined Abson Infotech as a Senior Developer. Here in Abson Infotech, I have managed projects.

Infobot Technology —Php Developer

Apr 2011 to Nov 2013

As a PHP developer, I have worked at Infobot Technology for 2 years and 7 months. Here in Infobot Technology, I have learned many new things.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all the above-mentioned information is in accordance with fact or

Name: UJJWAL BERA	Signature:
Place: Hooghly	Date:

truth up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the

above-mentioned particulars.